Guide to the Mary McCarthy Papers, circa 1915-2013 (bulk 1960-1989)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES V: PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - Personal correspondence to and from Mary McCarthy
    - Wayne, Donald, 1988 (Folder 232.4)
    - Wechsler, Jimmy (Folder 351.24)
    - Weidenfeld, George (Folder 351.25)
    - Weidenfeld, George, 1982, undated (Folder 232.5)
    - Weil, Annette, 1977 (Folder 232.6)
    - Weiss, Rudolph (Folder 351.26)
    - Weiss, Rudolf and Martha, 1978, undated (Folder 232.7)
    - Weissberger, L. Arnold, 1976-1979 (Folder 232.8)
    - Wensberg, Erik (Folder 351.27)
    - Wernham, Archibald, 1977-1979 (Folder 232.9)
    - Wernham, Hilda (Folder 351.28)
    - Wiggins, Jack, 1982-1983, undated (Folders 232.10 - 232.13)
    - Wiggins, Jack (Folder 351.29)
    - Wilk, Barbara, 1963, undated (Folder 232.14)
    - Williams, Jean E. (Folder 351.30)
    - Williams, Jean and Harold, 1977-1981, undated (Folder 233.1)
    - Williams, Tennessee (Folder 351.31)
    - Williams, Tim (Folder 351.32)
    - Wilson, Elena (Folder 352.52)
    - Winkelhorn, Sophie, 1951, undated (Folder 352.55)
    - Winkelhorn, Sophie, 1962-1983, undated (Folder 233.2)
    - Winslow, Philip, 1968-1969 (Folder 233.3)
    - Wittig, Monique, 1965-1986, undated (Folders 233.4 - 233.5)
    - About Monique Wittig, 1969-1974 (Folder 233.6)
    - Wojewoda, Cecylia, 1961-1988, undated (Folders 234.1 - 234.8)
    - Wojewoda, Cecylia, 1965-1989 (Folders 234.9 - 234.12)
    - Wojewoda, Cecylia, 1989 (Folder 352.3)
    - Wormser, Andre, 1974-1978 (Folder 235.1)
    - Wreszin, Michael (Folder 352.4)
    - Yglesias, J., 1971 (Folder 235.2)
    - Yoshino, Setsuko, 1970-1982 (Folders 235.3 - 235.4)
    - Yoshimo, Setsuko, 1988-1989 (Folder 352.6)
    - Young, Gavin, 1973-1982, undated (Folder 235.5)
    - Young, Marguerite, 1951 May 28 (Folder 352.7)
    - Young, Stark, 1958 (Folder 352.8)
    - Young-Bruehl Elizabeth, 1976-1982 (Folders 394.3 - 394.4)
    - Zabel, Morton D., 1964 (Folder 235.6)
    - Zabel, Morton D., 1940-1948 (Folder 352.9)
    - Zamojdo, Joanna, 1989 (Folder 352.10)
    - Zara, Louis, 1935 June 21 (Folder 352.11)
    - Miscellaneous — Domestic and secretarial help (Folder 353.1)
    - Miscellaneous — Family (Folder 353.2)
    - Miscellaneous — Holiday cards (Folder 353.3)
    - Miscellaneous — Politicians (including Georges Pompidou, William Cohen, William Hathaway, Edmund Muskie, and Daniel Patrick Moynihan) (Folder 353.11)
    - Miscellaneous — Reader mail (Folder 353.4)
    - Miscellaneous — Reader mail (Folder 353.4)
    - Miscellaneous — Reader mail — to Mr. Montemarana, 10 January 1980; (1 letter) (Folder 394.8)
    - Miscellaneous — Reader mail, 1977-1986; (1 letter) (Folder 394.11)
    - Miscellaneous — After death, 1990-1991 (Folder 353.5)
    - Miscellaneous — A to Z (Folder 353.6)
    - Unidentified, circa 1949-1989 (Folders 353.7 - 353.10)
    - Birthday and Christmas cards (Folder 361.4)
    - Miscellaneous personal correspondence: A-L (Folders 236.1 - 236.11)
    - Miscellaneous personal correspondence: M-Z (Folders 237.1 - 237.6)
    - Unidentified correspondents (Folders 237.7 - 237.9)
    - Holiday cards, birthday cards and social invitations (Box 238)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Broadwater, Bowden
      - Between Broadwater and McCarthy, 1945-1946; (9 folders) (Box 239)
      - Between Broadwater and McCarthy, 1946-1955; (10 folders) (Box 240)
      - Between Broadwater and McCarthy, 1955-1961, undated; (10 folders) (Box 241)
      - Broadwater, Bowden, 1949-1958, undated (Folders 353.12 - 353.15)
      - [RESTRICTED UNTIL STABILIZED — LES 2019] McCarthy to Broadwater, circa 1945-1988; (torn letters and photocopies) (Box 242)
      - McCarthy's Valentines to Broadwater, (7) (Box 242)
      - Broadwater, June (Folder 353.16)
    - Johnsrud, Harold
      - Johnsrud, Harold (Folder 356.3)
    - McCarthy and Preston Family
      - Davies, Myrtle, 1985-1988 (Folder 243.1)
      - Hooper, Bayard, 1978, undated (Folder 243.2)
      - Hooper, Mary McCarthy, 1972-1984 (Folder 243.3)
      - McCarthy, Eleanor, 1977 (Folder 243.4)
      - McCarthy, J. Harry (Folder 353.17)
      - McCarthy, J. Harry, 1952 (Folder 243.5)
      - McCarthy, James Kevin ("Flip"), 1967-1984, undated (Folder 243.6)
      - McCarthy, Kate, 1987, undated (Folder 243.7)
      - McCarthy, Kevin — includes letters from Mary McCarthy, 1949-1968, undated; (5 folders, some photocopies) (Box 244)
      - McCarthy, Kevin, 1942-1956, undated (Folder 353.18)
      - McCarthy, Lillah, 1971-1988, undated (Folder 243.8)
      - McCarthy, Mary Dabney, 1964-1988, undated (Folder 243.9)
      - McCarthy, Mary D. (Folder 353.19)
      - McCarthy, Preston and Ethel, 1983-1988, undated (Folder 243.10)
      - McCarthy, Preston (Folder 353.20)
      - McCarthy, Sophia (Folder 353.21)
      - Preston, Augusta Morganstern, 1932 (Folder 243.11)
      - Preston, Augusta Morganstern (Folder 354.1)
      - Preston, Augusta Morganstern (Folder 384.1)
      - Preston, Frank and Myrtle, 1964-1983, undated (Folders 243.12 - 243.13)
      - Preston, Frank (Preston, Thorgrimson and Horowiz Attorneys at Law) (Folder 354.2)
      - Preston, Isabel (Folder 354.3)
      - Preston, Mrs. Frank (Folder 354.4)
      - Prince, Augusta Dabney McCarthy, 1964-1988 (Folder 243.14)
      - Miscellaneous McCarthy relatives, 1983-1985 (Folder 243.15)
      - McCarthy Family correspondence, 1989 (Folder 365.10)
    - West Family
      - Brightman, Carol to Jim West (Folder 354.5)
      - West, Alison, 1973-1988 (Folders 245.1 - 245.4)
      - West, Danny and Bonnie, 1973-1988 (Folder 245.5)
      - West, Hope, 1962-1987 (Folders 245.6 - 245.8)
      - West, Hope (Folder 354.6)
      - McCarthy, Mary to James West, 1967 (Folder 246.1)
      - McCarthy, Mary to James West [The "Laos Letters"], 1968 (Folder 246.2)
      - McCarthy, Mary to James West (Folder 355.2)
      - West, James to Mary McCarthy, 1972-1986 (Folder 246.3)
      - West, James to Frances Kiernan (Folder 354.9)
      - West, James – information from trust (Folder 354.8)
      - West, James - after McCarthy's death (Folders 354.10 - 354.12)
      - West, James - after McCarthy's death (Folder 354.7)
      - West, James – notes (Folder 355.1)
      - West, Jonathan, 1977-1988 (Folder 246.4)
      - West, Rebecca (Folder 355.3)
      - West, Rebecca - correspondence with Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. (Folder 355.4)
      - West Family correspondence (Folder 355.5)
    - Wilson Family
      - Wilson, Edmund – photocopies, 1937 (Folder 355.6)
      - Wilson, Edmund, 1945-1956, 1971, undated (Folders 355.7 - 355.10)
      - Wilson, Edmund to Mary McCarthy, 1937-1949 (Folders 247.1 - 247.7)
      - Wilson, Edmund to Mary McCarthy, 1961-1971, undated (Folders 247.8 - 247.9)
      - Wilson, Edmund to Reuel Wilson, 1945-1949 (Folder 247.10)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Edmund Wilson, 1945 (Folder 247.11)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Edmund Wilson, 1944-1970; (photocopies - from the Beinecke Library?) (Folder 247.12)
      - To Mary McCarthy regarding Edmund Wilson and his papers, 1973 (Folder 247.13)
      - Publication of Wilson's journals, 1982 (Folder 247.14)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Reuel Wilson, 1946-1962, undated (Folders 384.4 - 384.5)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Reuel Wilson, 1961-1963 (Folder 384.6)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Reuel and Marcia Wilson, 1963-1976 (Folders 384.7 - 384.8)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Reuel and Marcia Wilson, 1977-1982 (Folder 385.1)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Reuel Wilson, 1983-1989 (Folders 385.2 - 385.3)
      - McCarthy, Mary to Natsuko Wilson, 1982-1987 (Folder 385.4)
      - Broadwater, Bowden to Reuel Wilson, 1948-1956, 1971 (Folder 384.3)
      - West, James to Reuel Wilson, 7 December 1981 (Folder 384.2)
      - West, James to Reuel Wilson, 24 January 1985 (Folder 385.5)
      - Wilson, Marcia and Jay, 1963-1971 (Folders 248.3 - 248.6)
      - Wilson, Marcia and Jay, 1972-1988, undated (Folders 249.1 - 249.6)
      - Wilson, Reuel, 1946-1988, undated (Boxes 250-251)
      - Wilson, Reuel and Marcia (Folder 355.12)
      - Wilson, Reuel, 1951-1959 (Folders 355.13 - 355.14)
      - Wilson, Elena, 1959-1979 (Folder 248.1)
      - Wilson, Helen, 1982 (Folder 248.2)
      - Wilson, Helen (Folder 355.11)
      - Wilson, Rosalind, 1944, 1981 (Folder 249.7)
      - Wilson, Rosalind (Folder 356.1)
      - Wilson, Susan Colston (Folder 356.2)
  - Correspondence Notebooks
    - Correspondence Notebooks, September 1980 - October 1982; (4 steno pads) (Folders 356.4 - 356.7)
    - Correspondence Notebooks, May 1983 - July 1984; (5 steno pads) (Box 357)
    - Correspondence Notebooks, August 1984 - June 1986; (6 steno pads) (Box 358)
    - Correspondence Notebooks, June 1986 - April 1988; (5 steno pads) (Box 359)
    - Correspondence Notebooks, July 1988 - August 1989, undated; (5 steno pads) (Box 360)
- SERIES VI: PERSONAL AND BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL
  - Books and Other Writing About McCarthy
    - The Company She Kept, by Doris Grumbach (1967)
      - Correspondence: Grumbach – McCarthy, 1965-1967 (Folders 91.13 - 91.14)
      - Publishers' and agents' correspondence, 1966-1967 (Folder 91.15)
      - Correspondence: Wilson – Coward-McCann, 1966 (Folder 91.16)
      - Manuscript notes [written by James West?] (Folder 92.1)
      - Transcripts of McCarthy interviews with Grumbach (Folder 92.2)
      - Galleys (Folder 92.3)
      - Corrected proofs (Folders 92.4 - 92.6)
      - Reviews (Folder 92.7)
      - Reviews — clippings (Folder 304.2)
    - Mary McCarthy: A Bibliography, by Sherli Evens Goldman (1968)
      - Correspondence: Goldman – McCarthy, 1965-1979 (Folder 93.1)
      - "A Comprehensive Bibliography of Mary McCarthy" — typescript, December 1965 (Folder 93.2)
    - Mary McCarthy: A Life, by Carol Gelderman (1988)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1988 (Folders 93.3 - 93.8)
      - Photo choices, December 1987 (Folder 93.9)
      - Reviews (Folder 93.10)
      - McCarthy's corrections and notes (Folder 93.11)
      - Gelderman's manuscript (Folders 94.1 - 94.5)
    - Writing Dangerously: Mary McCarthy and Her World, by Carol Brightman (1992)
      - Correspondence: Brightman – McCarthy, 1979-1988 (Folders 95.1 - 95.2)
      - Other work by Brightman (Folder 95.3)
    - Other Works about McCarthy
      - Eakin, Paul John. "Fiction in Autobiography: Ask Mary McCarthy No Questions," chapter in Fictions in Autobiography: Studies in the Art of Self-Invention, 1985 (Folder 304.1)
      - Flora, Joseph. "Mary McCarthy ..." [essay] in Dictionary of Literary Biography Yearbook, 1981 (Folder 96.1)
      - Hunting, Constance. "Some Sort of Joy," Puckerbrush Review (interview with McCarthy), 1982 (Folder 308.2)
      - Jelenski, Contantin and Edgardo Cazarinsky. "Memoire: Mary McCarthy," L'Institut National de l'Audiovisuel, 7 December 1982 (Folder 304.5)
      - Korelitz, Jean Hanff. "Book It: 'Memories of a Catholic Girlhood' ..." (Folder 96.2)
      - Mallon, Thomas. "Excited Scruples: Ideas of Human Responsibility in the Writings of Mary McCarthy" (Folders 96.3 - 96.4)
      - Munroe, Gretchen Himmele. "Mary McCarthy ..." [essay] in Dictionary of Literary Biography, vol. 2, American Novelists Since World War II, 1979 (Folder 96.5)
      - Niebuhr, Elizabeth, "The Art of Fiction, XXVII: Mary McCarthy," Paris Review, 1979 (Folder 308.1)
      - Steane, Nina. "Quite Contrary. Mary McCarthy." ("Based on a talk given to the Northampton Arts Association Literature Group, Feb. 4th 1971) — typescript draft (Folder 96.6)
      - Stock, Irvin. "A Closer Look at Mary McCarthy" — typescript, (photocopy) (Folder 96.7)
      - Stock, Irvin. "The Magic Mountain" — inscribed and signed offprint (Folder 96.7)
      - Stwertka, Eve, 2013; (2 pieces) (Folder 394.10)
      - Taylor, Gordon O. "Cast a Cold 'I': Mary McCarthy on Vietnam" — typescript, (photocopy) (Folder 96.8)
      - Trouard, Dawn Catherine. "The Charmed Circles of Mary McCarthy" — typescript copy of Master's thesis (Folder 96.9)
      - Van de Wouw, Josephine. "Mary McCarthy: The Quest for Truth" — typescript copy of doctoral thesis (Folder 96.10)
      - "Portrait of a Lady: Mary McCarthy," The Paris Metro, 15 February 1978 (Folder 393.1 (Oversize))
      - Vassar articles and ephemera, circa 1963-1982 (Folder 328.8)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1982, 1984 (Folder 328.9)
      - Exhibit and lecture flyers (Folder 328.10)
      - Unidentified French article (Folder 328.11)
      - Miscellaneous articles about Mary McCarthy (Folder 255.6)
      - Clippings of articles about McCarthy, circa 1949-1988; (6 folders) (Box 303)
      - Clippings with mentions of Mary McCarthy, circa 1957-1988; (2 folders) (Box 304)
      - German clippings about McCarthy, (some bound) (Boxes 305-306)
      - Clippings of foreign interviews (Folder 308.3)
      - Miscellaneous articles about Mary McCarthy, (photocopies) (Folder 307.5)
      - Miscellaneous interviews with Mary McCarthy, (photocopies) (Folder 307.6)
  - Address Books and Calendars
    - Address books (Folders 253.8 - 253.10)
    - Address books, (4 items) (Folder 361.1-361.2)
    - Address books, (2 items) (Folder 362.1)
    - Miscellaneous address lists and business cards (Folder 254.1)
    - Calendars, 1947 (Folder 253.1)
    - Calendars, 1948 (Folder 361.8)
    - Calendars, 1956 (Folder 253.15)
    - Calendars, 1957 (Folder 253.16)
    - Calendars, 1958 (Folder 253.17)
    - Calendars, 1959 (Folder 361.6)
    - Calendars, 1963 (Folder 262.1)
    - Calendars, 1967; (4 items) (Folders 253.2 - 253.3)
    - Calendars, 1967 (Folder 253.13)
    - Calendars, 1968 (Folder 253.4)
    - Calendars, 1970; (2 items) (Folder 262.2)
    - Calendars, 1970 (Folder 262.13)
    - Calendars, 1971 (Folder 253.14)
    - Calendars, 1971; (2 items) (Folder 253.5)
    - Calendars, 1972; (4 items) (Folders 262.3 - 262.4)
    - Calendars, 1972 (Folder 262.14)
    - Calendars — Items removed from 1972 calendar (262.14) (Folder 262.21)
    - Calendars, 1973; (4 items) (Folders 253.6 - 253.7)
    - Calendars, 1974; (3 items) (Folder 262.5)
    - Calendars, 1975; (3 items) (Folder 262.6)
    - Calendars, 1975 (Folder 262.15)
    - Calendar page, July 1975 (Folder 262.22)
    - Calendars, 1976; (3 items) (Folder 262.7)
    - Calendars, 1976 (Folder 262.16)
    - Calendars, 1981 (Folder 262.8)
    - Calendars, 1981 (Folder 363.1)
    - Calendars, 1983 (Folder 361.7)
    - Calendars, 1983; (2 items) (Folder 362.2)
    - Calendars, 1983-1984; (2 items) (Folder 362.3)
    - Calendars, 1984; (2 items) (Folder 362.7)
    - Calendars, 1985 (Folder 262.9)
    - Calendars, 1986 (Folder 362.4)
    - Calendars, 1986; (2 items) (Folder 362.8)
    - Calendars, 1988; (2 items) (Folder 362.9)
    - Calendars, 1988; (2 items) (Folder 362.5)
    - Calendars, 1988-1989; (2 items) (Folder 362.6)
    - James West — Address book (Folder 262.12)
    - James West — Calendars, 1974; (4 items) (Folders 262.10 - 262.11)
    - James West — Calendars, 1969-1970; (2 items) (Folder 262.18)
    - James West — Calendars, 1973-1974; (2 items) (Folder 262.19)
    - James West — Calendar, 1976 (Folder 262.20)
    - James West — Expense and tax book, 1976 (Folder 262.17)
  - Entertainment and Events
    - Entertainment record book, circa 1963-1983 (Box 252)
    - Party invitation lists, 1977 (Folder 363.2)
    - Party invitation lists, undated (Folder 363.15)
    - RSVPs and thank yous, 1977 (Folder 363.3)
    - Event lists, 1977-1989 (Folder 363.9)
    - Receipts, 1981 (Folder 363.10)
    - Receipts, 1986 (Folder 363.11)
    - Receipts, 1989 (Folder 363.12)
    - Marriage to James West — telegraphs, list, map, 15 April 1961 (Folder 254.2)
    - McCarthy's 60th birthday — guest list and seating charts, 21 June 1972 (Folder 254.3)
    - McCarthy's 65th Birthday, 1977 (Folder 363.13)
    - McCarthy's 75th Birthday, 1987 (Folder 363.14)
    - McCarthy's 75th Birthday — itinerary, 1989 (Folder 361.5)
  - Death
    - Obituaries (Folder 363.7)
    - Obituaries (Folder 363.8)
    - Memorial service at The Pierpont Morgan Library, 8 November 1989 (Folders 254.4 - 254.5)
    - Memorial service at The Pierpont Morgan Library, 8 November 1989; (audiotape) (Box 294)
    - Memorial Service at Vassar College, 5 May 1990 (Folders 254.6 - 254.8)
    - Memorial Service Guestbook (Box 391)
    - Vassar memorial, 1989-1990 (Folder 363.6)
    - Tombstone — John Stevens Shop (Folder 368.10)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook-diary of Simon Manly Preston, McCarthy's great-grandfather (Box 296)
    - McCarthy's scrapbook, 1956,1962 (Box 297)
    - McCarthy's scrapbook, 1967-1970 (Box 298)
  - Medical Records
    - McCarthy medical information (Box 256)
    - Insurance documents — Aetna, 1988-1991 (Folder 364)
    - Insurance documents — Medicare (Folder 366.3)
    - American Hospital of Paris (Folder 365.2)
    - Eastern Maine Medical Center — Dr. Thomas Palmer (Folder 365.3)
    - New York Hospital — Dr. Fred Plum (Folder 365.4)
    - Dr. Thaddeus Jozefowicz and Bertel Bren (Folder 365.5)
    - Medical histories, reports and service logs, 1988-1989 (Folder 365.6)
    - Payments to doctors, after insurance payment received 1988-1989 (Folder 366.1)
    - Medical services not reimbursable (for income tax) (Folder 366.2)
    - Documents accompanying x-rays, April 1982 (Folder 366.4)
    - X-rays, April 1982 (Folder 366.5)
    - X-rays, April 1982 (Folder 391.2)
    - X-rays, April 1982 (Folder 393.6 (Oversize))
    - James West's medical documents (Folder 365.7)
    - Miscellaneous medical records, 1967-1972 (Folder 365.8)
    - Miscellaneous medical records, 1981-1989 (Folder 365.9)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Biographical reference sources - entries and updates, 1973-1989 (Folders 255.1 - 255.3)
    - Biographical reference sources - entries and updates (Folder 361.3)
    - Annie Wright Seminary, 1959-1975 (Folder 255.1)
    - Annie Wright Seminary diploma, 11 June 1929 (Folder 393.3 (Oversize))
    - Membership Cards (Box 391)
    - Press Cards (Box 392)
    - Press pass — New York Review of Books (Folder 253.12)
    - Credit card directory (Folder 253.11)
    - Note cards — recipes (Folder 87.4)
    - Library card — Stonington, Connecticut (Folder 257.6)
    - Library card — Bibliotheque nationale de France (temporary), 1964 (Folder 257.20)
    - McCarthy family genealogy (Folder 363.5)
    - Miscellaneous family information, undated (Folder 255.4)
    - Miscellaneous cards, menus, fragments, and other items (Folder 309.1)
    - Clippings — family (Folder 309.2)
    - Clippings — Kevin McCarthy (Folder 309.3)
    - Clippings, etc. collected by James West, circa 1960-1981 (Folder 309.4)
- SERIES VII: LEGAL AND FINANCIAL MATERIAL
  - Legal Documents
    - Attorney correspondence — Benjamin C. O'Sullivan (Holtzman, Wise and Shepard), 1981-1989 (Folder 257.7)
    - Attorney correspondence — Cleary, Gottlieb, Steen and Hamilton, 1960-1986 (Folder 257.8)
    - Attorney correspondence — Cleary, Gottlieb, Steen and Hamilton, 1986 (Folder 369.3)
    - Attorney correspondence — Lorraine Houck, 1990 (Folder 369.1)
    - Attorney correspondence — Calvin True, 1990-1991 (Folder 369.2)
    - Birth certificates (Folder 367.2)
    - Copyright — film and television rights, 1980-1982 (Folder 257.19)
    - Death certificates (Folder 367.3)
    - Divorce — Harold C. Johnsrud, 1936 (Folder 257.16)
    - Divorce — Edmund Wilson, 1945-1946 (Folder 257.17)
    - Marriage certificates, 1933, 1946 (Folder 257.18)
    - Equitable Insurance — New Yorker retirement annuity (Folder 367.4)
    - Paris apartment — original purchase, 1951-1962 (Folder 257.9)
    - French estate — Paris apartment — appraisal (Folder 367.5)
    - French estate — Paris apartment — receipts for expenses (Folder 367.6)
    - French estate — Paris apartment — sale (Folder 367.7)
    - French estate — Will, 1990 (Folder 367.8)
    - French estate — Will, 1969 (Folder 367.9)
    - French estate — Will, 1967-1968 (Folder 367.10)
    - French estate — Will, 1964 (Folder 368.1)
    - Hannah Arendt trust, 1977-1978 (Folder 394.18)
    - Hannah Arendt trust — Ronnie Beiner, 1981 (Folder 394.17)
    - Hannah Arendt trust, 1984-1985 (Folder 368.5)
    - Hannah Arendt trust, 1976-1990; (4 folders) (Box 378)
    - Homeowners insurance, Paris — Christian de Clarens et Fils, 1978-1991 (Folder 368.3)
    - Homeowners insurance, Paris — Security Storage, 1983-1991 (Folder 368.4)
    - Insurance — Miscellaneous, 1983-1991 (Folder 369.4)
    - Literary Trust — A.M. Heath, 1990 (Folder 368.7)
    - Memorial donations in Mary’s name (Folder 368.6)
    - Passports, 1952-1978 (Folders 257.1 - 257.5)
    - Passport, 1967 (Box 392)
    - Personal property — Shipping from Paris to U.S., 1990 (Folder 368.8)
    - Power of Attorney, 1968, 1989 (Folder 369.5)
    - Probate court documents — Hancock County, Maine (Folder 368.9)
    - Travel documents — Poland, 1960 (Folder 257.21)
    - U.S. estate — will, 1955 (Folder 257.10)
    - U.S. estate — wills, 1969, 1982 (Folder 367.1)
    - U.S. estate — wills, 1964-1982 (Folder 369.6)
    - Estate of Augusta M. Preston, 1954-1956 (Folder 257.11)
    - U.S. State Department — records relating to McCarthy, 1946-1968 (Folder 257.12)
    - U.S. State Department — records relating to James West, 1965-1967 (Folder 257.13)
    - Freedom of Information-Privacy Act requests (Leland Tolman file), 1975-1979 (Folder 257.14)
    - Freedom of Information-Privacy Act requests, 1968-1977 (Folder 257.15)
    - Vassar College – Mary McCarthy Papers, 1983-1988; (5 folders) (Box 383)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1964 (Folder 257.22)
  - Lillian Hellman Lawsuit
    - Court documents, 1980-1984 (Folders 258.1 - 258.6)
    - First interrogatories — Drafts of answers, 1980 (Folder 258.7)
    - Preparation for McCarthy deposition, 1981 (Folder 258.8)
    - McCarthy's notes and lists, circa 1980-1984 (Folder 259.1)
    - Dick Cavett Show prep material for McCarthy appearance, 1979 (Folder 259.2)
    - Attorney correspondence — Holtzman, Wise and Shepard (Benjamin O'Sullivan), 1980-1986 (Folder 259.3)
    - Attorney correspondence — Holtzman, Wise and Shepard, 1980-1981 (Folder 259.4)
    - Attorney correspondence — Cahill, Gordon and Reindel (Floyd Abrams), 1984 (Folder 259.5)
    - Attorney correspondence — Debevoise and Plimpton (John Koeltl), 1981-1984 (Folder 259.6)
    - Correspondence — Beichman, Arnold, 1982-1983 (Folder 259.7)
    - Correspondence — Burck, Jacob, 1980 (Folder 259.8)
    - Correspondence — Carr, Virginia Spencer, 1980 (Folder 259.9)
    - Correspondence — Collingwood, Charles, 1980 (Folder 259.10)
    - Correspondence — Epstein, Barbara (New York Review of Books), 1984 (Folder 259.11)
    - Correspondence — Furnas, Helen, 1980-1983 (Folder 259.12)
    - Correspondence — Gardiner, Muriel, 1980-1983 (Folder 259.13)
    - Correspondence — Gelderman, Carol, 1980-1981 (Folder 259.14)
    - Correspondence — Gellhorn, Martha, 1980-1981 (Folder 259.15)
    - Correspondence — Goldwater, Walter, circa 1973, 1977, 1980 (Folder 259.16)
    - Correspondence — Hale, Sheila, 1980 (Folder 259.17)
    - Correspondence — Hardwick, Elizabeth, 1980 (Folder 259.18)
    - Correspondence — Hite, John, 1980 (Folder 259.19)
    - Correspondence — Kanfer, Stefan (Time magazine), 1980 (Folder 259.20)
    - Correspondence — Paturis, Cleo, 1981, 1984 (Folder 259.21)
    - Correspondence — Silvers, Robert (New York Review of Books), 1981, 1984 (Folder 259.22)
    - Correspondence — Spender, Stephen, 1983 (Folder 259.23)
    - Correspondence — Taylor, Harold, 1980 (Folder 259.24)
    - Correspondence — Zilahy, Piroska, 1980 (Folder 259.25)
    - Correspondence — Friends and acquaintances, 1980-1984 (Folder 259.26)
    - Correspondence — Miscellaneous, 1980-1984 (Folder 259.27)
    - Reader mail, 1980-1984, 1987 (Folder 259.28)
    - Clippings, 1980-1988 (Folder 259.29)
    - Clippings, (7 folders) (Box 310)
    - Hellman (Folder 370.1)
    - Hellman Letter (Folder 370.2)